Robert Hare Papers 1764-1859 Mss.B.H22
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence
  - C. Hare to Robert Hare, [1841] April 13 (Box 4)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p., add. Concerning the uproar over the bank and Biddle. News of the country.
  - Letter to Robert Hare, [1841] April 25 (Box 4)
  - Petty Vaughan to Robert Hare, 1841 May 14; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. Sends ticket to the Sloane museum.
  - William Vaughan. Pass..., 1841 May 14 (Box 2)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S. 2 items. Tickets of admission to [Robert Hare] to attend the Royal Institution.
  - Mr. Murray to Robert Hare, [1841] May 17 (Box 4)
    L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Refers him to another editor for his article.
  - British and Foreign Aboriginies' Protective Society. Ticket of admission..., 1841 May 17 (Box 2)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. Ticket of admission for the reserved seats gallery.
  - London Athenaeum to Robert Hare, 1841 May 18 (Box 2)
    London, Printed L. filled in in ms. S.: Edw[ar]d Magrath, Secy. Offers him courtesy of the Athenaeum for two months.
  - Michael Faraday. Ticket of admission..., 1841 May 21; Faraday, Michael, 1791-1867 (Box 2)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S. 1p. Ticket of admission to the Royal Institution for Dr. [Robert] Hare.
  - Henry Grotton to Mr. Powell, 1841 May 24 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. Returns books.
  - Colonel Sykes to Robert Hare, 1841 May 24; Sykes, Colonel, (William Henry), 1790-1872 (Box 2)
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Invitation to dinner.
  - William Guillemard to Robert Hare, 1841 May 26; Guillemard, William Henry, 1815-1887 (Box 2)
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. and add. Could not meet him at Ogilby's, but proposes a week-end in the country.
  - Pass for admission of A. G. Ralston to Apsley House, [1841] May 26, 27 (Box 4)
  - William Stuart to Robert Hare, 1841 May 27 (Box 2)
    Liverpool, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Must know the date of his sailing, else he cannot secure passage. Lists cost on the Cunard line.
  - Robert Graham to Robert Hare, 1841 May 29 (Box 2)
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 3p. Thanks him for his publications on chemistry and tornadoes. Refers to Faraday and W. Vaughan.
  - Petty Vaughan to Robert Hare, 1841 May 29 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Business. Asks him to hear the "Charity Children at St Pauls" next Tuesday.
  - M. A. Wellesley to Robert Hare, [1841] May 29 (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 3p. Has been ill but is better, so asks that he call at 2:00 tomorrow.
  - D. B. Reid Pass..., 1841 May; Reid, D. B. (David Boswell), 1805-1863 (Box 2)
    Printed D.S. with initials: D.B.R. 2p. Ticket of admission to hear a lecture on the chemistry of the air.
  - J. W. G. Gutch to Robert Hare, 1841 June 1; Gutch, John Wheeley Gough, 1809-1862 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges receipt of his papers for the meteorological society.
  - Petty Vaughan to Robert Hare, 1841 June 1; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. Refers to Professor Graham's receipt of the package.
  - William Henry Fitton to Robert Hare, 1841 June 1; Fitton, William Henry, 1780-1861 (Box 2)
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 3p. Asks him to meeting of the Geological Society, where he will be introduced.
  - John Guillemard to Dr. Hare, 1841 June 2 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. and add. Sorry they did not meet, but he had misdirected his letter.
  - Robert Hare to W. R. Gwin?, 1841 June 4 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the shipment of chemical apparatus.
  - W. R. Gwin (?) to Robert Hare, 1841 July 3 (Box 2)
    L. 1p. and add. Will ship chemical equipment.
  - Robert Hare to Dominique François Jean Arago, 1841 Sept. 16 (Box 2)
    L. 12p. In French. Draft. Concerning his work on chemistry, electricity, etc. Refers to the APS.
  - Robert Hare to Count Anatol Demidorff, 1841 Sept. 21 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. Copy. His process of converting platina. On same sheet is letter from F. Campbell Stewart to Hare; Oct. 26, 1841.
  - F. Campbell Stewart to Robert Hare, 1841 Oct 26
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Has taken care of the parcels and articles he forwarded for dispersal. Forwards copy of letter to Demidorff. On same sheet as letter from Hare to Demidorff; Sept. 21, 1841.
  - I. J. Chapman to Robert Hare, [1841] (Box 4)
    Thursday. A.L.S. 3p. and add. Encloses orders to get him into meetings of some societies.
  - William Ogilby to Robert Hare, [1841] (Box 5)
    A.L.S. 2p. Invitation to dinner.
  - Chevalier De Gregory to Robert Hare, 1842 Jan. 16 (Box 2)
    Paris, L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Concerning birds of America.
  - A.P.S. Meeting (Extract), 1842 Jan. 21; American Philosophical Society. (Box 2)
    D. 3p. In French. Abstract of a minute, concerning an oral communication made by Dr. Hare.
    Printed (in English): APS Proceedings, vol. 2, 142-143.
  - William E. Channing to Robert Hare, 1842 March 2; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842 (Box 2)
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Asks his opinion of his son, William Channing. Invites him to Boston. Refers to Silliman.
  - A.P.S. Minute of communication made by Robert Hare, 1842 April 1; American Philosophical Society.
    D. 3p. and end. In French. Translated by E.Durand.
    Printed: APS Proceedings, II, 161-162.
    Not located 4/2010
  - E. Durand. Translation of experiment..., 1842 May 27 (Box 2)
  - Robert Hare to Count [George, i.e., Igor Frankovitch?] Cancrin, 1842 May 29 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p., end. Copy. Analyses of ores for platinum, etc. ----Copy. 4p., end. 10x8.
  - Robert Hare to Arthur (?) and Thomas Dyke Acland, 1842 Sept. 29
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the forwarding of a pamphlet of his to them.
    Formerly B H22.3.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1843 Oct. 18; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 4p., add., end. Concerning some of his recent publications containing theories of galvanism.
  - R.Hare Concerning Samuel Breck... "Black Cockade", 1843 Nov. (Box 2)
    D. 14p. ----Partial copy. 1p. For Breck item, see: Breck. Historical Sketch...paper money. Concerning Samuel Breck and his comments on the wearers of the "Black Cockade", in his speech on Continental Currency, before the APS.
  - Robert Hare to Dr. Staples, 1844 Aug. 15 (Box 2)
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Cannot run for office in politics. Is for stricter naturalization laws.
  - John J. Kane to Robert Hare, 1844 Nov. 22 (Box 2)
    Sing Sing, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Thanks for information for placing lightning rods on his dwelling.
  - Robert Hare to "Fellow Citizens", 1844; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 2)
    L.S.: Washington. 2p. and end. To the Inquirer. Essay on patriotism, signed "Washington".
  - Concerning the election of a president for the APS, [1844?]; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858
  - Robert Hare to ---, 1845 May 8; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, A.L. 1p. Draft. Concerning platinum.
  - C. F. Durant to the Mayor of New York, 1845 Sept. 2; Durant, C. F. (Charles Ferson), 1805-1873 (Box 2)
    Printed L. 6p. and end. by R.Hare. Concerning the explosion.
  - U. of Pennsylvania Board of Trustees to Robert Hare, 1845 Dec. 8; University of Pennsylvania. Trustees (Box 2)
    A.L.S.: Geo: Emlen, Jr. 1p. Concerning some alterations he made on his property which impinges on the University property.
  - Foot and Davies to Robert Hare, 1845 Dec. 31 (Box 2)
    New York, L. 1p., end. Concerning court decree on the J. I. Clark estate.
  - George Emlen to Benjamin W. Richards, 1846 Feb. 9; Emlen, George, 1784-1850 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Lists alleged encroachments made upon University property by Robert Hare.
  - Robert Hare to B. W. Richards and William Rawle, 1846 Feb. 25 (Box 2)
    L.S. 5p., end. Concerning his alleged encroachments on University property.
  - U. of Pennsylvania Board of Trustees to Robert Hare, 1846 March 3; University of Pennsylvania. Trustees (Box 2)
    L.S.: Geo[rge] Emlen, Jr. 2p. Concerning his encroachments on University property.
  - U. of Pennsylvania Board of Trustees to Robert Hare, 1846 March 7; University of Pennsylvania. Trustees (Box 2)
    A.L.S.: Geo[rge] Emlen, Jr. 1p. and add. Forwards papers.
  - Robert Hare to ---, 1846 May
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Draft(?). Concerning giving a lecture about his life and work, including his positions at William and Mary and Pennsylvania.
    Formerly B H22.1.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    Purchased with 509:L56, October 3 1961.
  - James S. Gwynne. Description of his patented process..., 1846 Sept. 3 (Box 2)
    D. 3p. and end. Description of his patented process of extracting stearic acid.
  - B. Silliman, Jr. to Robert Hare, 1846 Sept. 28; Silliman, Benjamin, Jr., 1816-1885 (Box 2)
    New Haven, L.S. 2p. and P.S. by B. Silliman, Sr., end. Thanks for his commendation, for he was given the position.
  - Joseph M. Wightman to Robert Hare, 1846 Oct. 6; Wightman, Joseph M. (Joseph Milner), 1812-1885 (Box 2)
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p., end. and add. Concerning Arago's polariscope.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1846 Dec. 29; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 2)
    Princeton, A.L.S. 4p., end. Concerning the Smithsonian and his office there. Concerning Hare's manuscript on the constitution of matter.
  - Robert Hare to H. C. Beck, 1847 April 23
    A.N. in 3rd per. 1p. Hopes to avail himself of H. C. Beck's invitation for Saturday next.
  - William Rush to Robert Hare, 1847 May 17; Rush, William, 1801-1864 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p., end. Praises him as a teacher of chemistry and is sorry he has resigned from the University.
  - William De Benst to Robert Hare, 1847 July 15 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Wishes to know where to put his chemicals and equipment which are now at present at the University.
  - Eben N. Horsford to Robert Hare, 1847 July 29; Horsford, Eben Norton, 1818-1893 (Box 2)
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p. Answers question dealing with chemistry.
  - Robert Hare to the Editor of the American Journal of Science, 1848 April 8; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Draft. Attacks a man's article on his misinterpretation his article on tornadoes.
  - Franklin Institute. Resolutions pertaining to Dr. Hare's deposit..., 1848 May 17,18 (Box 2)
    D.S.: Will[ia]m Hamilton. 1p. Resolutions pertaining to Dr. Hare's deposit of his electrical machine and blow-pipe for melting platinum.
  - Thos. A. White to Robert Hare, 1848 Sept. 24 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Asks him to return books.
  - Walter R. Johnson to Robert Hare, 1848 Sept. 25 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, printed L. with P.S. in initials. 3p. and add. Lists members of the AAAS.
  - Thomas H. White to Robert Hare, 1848 Oct. 20 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p., end. and add. Religion.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1848 Nov. 16; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 2)
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p., end. Has received his gift of chemical apparatus and wants a letter of donation.
  - W. Barker to Thomas Hazard, 1849 Jan. 14 (Box 2)
    Portsmouth, A.L.S. 1p., end. Estimation of total catch of fish in Rhode Island and its sale.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1849 Jan. 19; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 2)
    Washington, A.L.S. 4p., end. Concerning his gift of apparatus to the Smithsonian. Will study his article on credit.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1849 January 30; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 2)
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks to borrow books on chemistry.
  - Anthony and Emerson to Robert Hare, 1849 Feb. 18 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, L. 1p., end. and add. Forwards a churn and asks for the results of his experiments on it, if he will be so kind.
  - John Wilkinson to Robert Hare, 1849 May 11 (Box 2)
    Germantown, Pennsylvania, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerning plows and fertilizers.
  - Smithsonian Institution to Robert Hare, 1849 Aug. 1; Smithsonian Institution. (Box 2)
    L.S.: Joseph Henry. 1p. Notifies him of election to honorary membership.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1849 Oct. 26; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 2)
    L.S.: Joseph Henry. 1p., end. Concerning the shipment of his chemical apparatus and evaluation of it.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1849 Dec. 15; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the shipment of his chemical apparatus to the Institution.
  - Robert Hare to ----, 1850 Jan. 27; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L. 2p. Draft. Inquires as to attempts to recover nitrogen form the air, for fertilizer.
  - William A. Tatem to Robert Hare, 1850 Jan. 31 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p., end. and add. Pays for lectures at the University taken years before.
  - John Etheridge to Robert Hare, 1850 Feb. 14; Etheridge, John (Box 3)
    A.L.S.: Jo[h]n Etheridge. 1p., end. From U.S. Navy Department. His manuscript was returned by error.
  - Robert Hare to Joseph Henry, 1850 April 14; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning sparks from flint and steel and those from quartz.
  - John Rehn to Robert Hare, 1850 May 3 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. His father is out of town.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1850 May 11; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 3p., end. Friendly letter. His apparatus for the Smithsonian. His course on electricity.
  - John J. Kane to Robert Hare, 1850 June 14 (Box 3)
    Sing Sing, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Questions a purported discovery by Paine on the use of electricity.
  - Robert Hare to Daniel W. Coxe, 1850 October 3; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L.S. 3p. and end. Draft. Comparing English miners with U.S. slaves.
  - Robert Hare to John Cook, 1850 October; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. and end. Draft. Offers him use of his patent for the preservation of flesh used for tallow.
  - J. Stuart Gwynne to Robert Hare, 1850 Nov. 2; Gwynne, James Stuart (Box 3)
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. end. Needs letters of introduction for a trip to Europe.
  - Hart to Robert Hare, 1850 Nov. 4 (Box 3)
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Has discussed his note with other people interested in agriculture.
  - Robert Hare to the Mayor of New York, 1850 Nov. 20; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L. 3p. and end. Concerning the prevention of putrefaction in meat.
  - Smithsonian Institution to Robert Hare, 1850 Nov. 25; Smithsonian Institution. (Box 3)
    L.S.: Joseph Henry. 1p., end. Notifies him he may attend the meetings of the Board of Regents whenever he desires.
  - Robert Hare to Charles Cumming, 1850 Nov. 28; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p., end. and end. Concerning his patented process.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1851 Feb. 24; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p., end. Authorizes, in the name of the Smithsonian, his use of ozone apparatus before the Franklin Institute.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1851 Feb. 28; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 3p., end. AAAS wishes to publish his remarks on government.
  - Smithsonian Institution to Robert Hare, 1851 April 28; Smithsonian Institution. (Box 3)
    A.L.S.: E. Foreman. 1p., end. Is shipping apparatus which was inadvertently ommitted in shipment.
  - Smithsonian Institution to Robert Hare, 1851 May 15; Smithsonian Institution. (Box 3)
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Will ship apparatus today.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1851 June 10; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 3p., end. Concerning the shipment of apparatus to the Smithsonian. Friendly letter, praising him in his research.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1851 Oct. 21; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p., end. Will discuss differences in their opinions on the transferrence of his apparatus to the Smithsonian.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1851 Dec. 11; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the transferrence of his aparatus to the Smithsonian.
  - William F. Channing to Robert Hare, 1851 Dec. 14; Channing, William F. (William Francis), 1820-1901 (Box 3)
    Boston, A.L.S. 12p. Comments on current events, especially the slave question. Tornado.
  - F. Vose to Robert Hare, 1851 Dec. 26 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p., end. Wishes to rent from him.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1852 Jan. 12; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter. Is shipping apparatus immediately. Smithsonian news.
  - M. F. Maury to Robert Hare, 1852 Jan. 17; Maury, Matthew Fontaine, 1806-1873 (Box 3)
    Washington, L.S. 2p., end. Meteorological questions.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1852 April 27; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 4p. Authorizes that he hire a man for the Smithsonian to take care of his apparatus. Concerning his, Espy's and the Smithsonian's interest in tornadoes and work being done on tornadoes by Blodget.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1852 May 4; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning his apparatus and the fact that Silliman, who had just lectured, gave credit for the apparatus. Describes the building of the Smithsonian.
  - R. P. Stevens to Robert Hare, 1852 July 2 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning his and Espy's theories of tornadoes. Describes several tornadoes he has seen.
  - Robert Hare to Joseph Henry, 1852 Sept. 2 (Box 3)
    Darlington, Pennsylvania, L. 1p. Duplicate. Agreement between William De Benst and the Smithsonian for the repair of the apparatus he presented to the Smithsonian.
  - Robert Hare to Joseph Henry, 1852 Sept. 12 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p. Draft. Concerning De Benst and his agreement to repair apparatus presented to the Smithsonian.
  - Robert Hare to Judge Rogers, 1852 Oct. 4 (Box 3)
    A.L. 2p. and end. Draft. His ideas of the War of 1812.
  - Robert Hare. On money, 1852? (Box 3)
    A.D. 1p.
  - Robert Hare to "my dear Frederick", 1853 Jan. 27 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. Draft. Difficulty with having work done.
  - Margaretta H. Morris to Mrs. Harriett Clark Hare, 1853 Feb. 17; Morris, Margaretta Hare, 1797-1867 (Box 3)
    Germantown, A.L.S. 3p. Copies a prayer by, and the epitaph of, their mutual "ancestress", Mrs. Ann Willing.
  - J. C. Dobbins to F. P. Stanton, 1853 Dec. 19; Dobbins, James Cochrane, 1814-1857 (Box 3)
    L.S. 1p. and end. States the amount, in answer to inquiry of Dr. Hare, expended on Espy's salary, etc.
  - Robert Hare to Mr. Tucker, 1854 March 2 (Box 3)
    L. 4p., end. Draft. Replies to newspaper letter on copyrights.
  - S. B. Halliday to Robert Hare, 1854 April 21 (Box 3)
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning the possibility of making guano from fish.
  - Robert Hare to S. B. Halliday, 1854 May 26; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L. 2p. Draft. Concerning the making of guano from fish.
  - Robert Hare to Mr. Moodie, 1854 July 9; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L. 1p. Draft. Incomplete. Explaining the expenditure of funds for spiritualism.
  - William De Benst to Robert Hare, 1854 Aug. 1 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning tools to repair equipment at the Smithsonian. Refers to Henry.
  - Smithsonian Institution to Robert Hare, 1854 Oct. 9; Smithsonian Institution. (Box 3)
    Washington, L.S.: Joseph Henry. 1p. Notification of meeting.
  - R. E. Rogers to Robert Hare, 1854 Nov. 23; Rogers, R. E., (Robert Empie), 1813-1884 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 1p. Encloses money which is interest due him.
  - R. H. Hare to John H. Enser, 1854 Nov. 24 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p. and end. by R. Hare.
  - Wilson N. Cary. Protest of Robert Hare's bill of exchange, 1854 Nov. 25 (Box 3)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S. 2p.
  - Robert Hare to ----, 1855 April 18 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L. 3p. Draft. Concerning a publication of his, and spiritualism.
  - Partridge and Brittan. Agreement with Robert Hare, 1855 May 21 (Box 3)
    D. 2p. and end. Copy. Agreement with Robert Hare for publication of his book on spiritualism.
  - Robert Hare to Partridge and Brittan, 1855 June 26 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L. 3p. and end. Copy. His book on spiritualism must be done here since "the spirits wish it to be done here under their auspices."
  - J. D. Knight to Robert Hare, 1855 July 20 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning types of oil.
  - Robert Hare. Bills and receipts for expenditures at Baltimore, 1855 July-Nov.; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    D. 8 items. Various sizes.
  - G. Huff to Robert Hare, 1855 Sept. 19 (Box 3)
    Lexington, Kentucky, A.L.S. 1p. Asks for battery since he believes Hare "to be the best electrician in this country."
  - S. B. Halliday to Robert Hare, 1855 Nov. 8 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning the manufacture of fish guano.
  - Charles Partridge to Robert Hare, 1855 Dec. 3 (Box 3)
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Concerning publications of his by Partridge & Britton.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1855 Dec. 17; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p. Will hire De Benst. Friendly letter.
  - Robert Hare. On the frequent use of the word, "well", 1856 January; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    A.D.S.: Americanus. 1p. and end. Draft. Essay on the frequent use of the word "well".
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1856 Feb. 18 (Box 3)
  - Partridge and Brittan. Account with Robert Hare, 1856 Feb.-Oct. (Box 3)
    D. 1p.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1856 March 21; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. end. Smithsonian affairs. (Previously cataloged as 1836.)
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1856 April 3; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    Washington, L.S. 3p. The Smithsonian will publish his article on tornadoes and lists costs and stipulates contents. Concerning his electrical apparatus and De Benst. Meteorological comments.
  - Robert Hare to Mr. Wilson, 1856 April 4
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Recommends him to Dr. William Channing of Boston for questions on electricity.
    Formerly B H22.2. Not located 4/2010
  - George Gourlay. Promissory note to Robert Hare, 1856 April 28 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p.
  - E. Meriam to Robert Hare, 1856 May 3; Meriam, Ebenezer,1794-1864. (Box 3)
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 1p. Asks if he were the first to insulate wires for electrical experiments under water.
  - S. Austin Allibone to Robert Hare, 1856 May 5; Allibone, S. Austin (Samuel Austin), 1816-1889 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks if he were the first to insulate wires for electrical experiments under water.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1856 May 9; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning De Benst and the Smithsonian. Friendly letter.
  - J. B. Smyth to Robert Hare, 1856 May 12 (Box 3)
    Rockford, Ill; A.L.S. 1p. Asks for name of a cheap acid to aid in making of cornstarch.
  - Pratt and Freeman to Robert Hare, 1856 May 20 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. Notifies him of an "oil manufactured from...Coal".
  - Charles B. Boyle to Robert Hare, 1856 June 30 (Box 3)
    Garison's Landing, N.Y., A.L.S. 3p. Concerning photography and news of new developments. Refers to his spiritualism.
  - Edmond Hurst. Protest of a note by George Gourlay to Robert Hare, 1856 July 31. (Box 3)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S.: Edmond Hurst, Notary Public. 1p. and end.
  - J. L. Hill to Robert Hare, 1856 Sept. 1 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning chemical problems and his solutions: ammonia, light, oxygen.
  - J. B. Smyth to Robert Hare, 1856 Sept. 30 (Box 3)
    Rockford, Ill.; A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the making of starch from corn.
  - J. B. Smyth to Robert Hare, 1856 Oct. 16 (Box 3)
    Rockford, Ill.; A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the making of starch from corn.
  - Robert Hare to A. D. Bache, 1856 Oct. 31; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    L. 4p. and end. Concerning standard weights and measures.
  - Sarah Gibbs to Robert Hare, 1856? Nov.3 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p. and add. Sends copy of receipt.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1856 Nov. 3; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning his communication on weights and measures.
  - J. B. Smyth to Robert Hare, 1856 Dec. 15 (Box 3)